# **SVITLANA ZASTER**

Houston, TX 77057 | Phone: (832)692-2564 | Email: szaster@protonmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/svitlana-zaster-77a9a06b | GitHub: https://github.com/szaster

Portfolio: https://szaster.github.io/SZPortfolio-React/

#### **SUMMARY**

Full stack coding camp graduate with a background in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL, MongoDB, and other tech. Professional strengths include creative problem-solving, leadership, enthusiasm, and effective time management. Detail-oriented with an analytical mindset acquired during 10+ years of experience in scientific research, programming, and education. Life-long learner, self-starter, adaptable team-player, diligent, open-minded, flexible, and creative. Excellent presentation, communication, and organizational skills. Eager to continue to grow professionally, add value to the company, and build meaningful projects.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, NoSQL, GrapgQL, Wolfram Language, Python.

Frameworks: React, Redux, Express, Passport, Node, Material-UI, Materialize, Bootstrap, jQuery, Seguelize, Mongoose.

Other Tech: MongoDB, mySQL, GitHub, GitKraken, LaTeX, Wolfram Mathematica.

# **PROJECTS**

Letflex: http://letflex.herokuapp.com/ | GitHub: https://github.com/szaster/Letflex

- Description: Letflex is Netflix clone app featuring movie search name or keywords. Users can watch trailers, add movies to favorites, comment, review, and discuss movies. Letflex has a blog/dashboard feature with recommendations and movie reviews.
- Role: Mostly worked on back-end, authorization flow, and on the connection with front-end. Created data models for MongoDB Atlas database, wrote Express route controllers, configured Passport, and implemented user sign-in authorization with Google OAuth.
- Tools/languages: React, Redux, Express, Passport, Mongoose, Node, Heroku, MongoDB Atlas.

IdeaExpo: http://ideaexpo.herokuapp.com/ | GitHub: https://github.com/szaster/IdeaEXPO

- Description: Web application allows to search, post, develop business ideas, and find collaborators on the ideas of interest.
- Role: Created models for MySQL database, wrote Express route controllers, configured Passport, implemented user sign-in authorization with Google OAuth.
- Tools/languages: HTML, Javascript, CSS, Materialize CSS, MySQL, Sequelize, Express, Node, Handlebars, Heroku.

Middle Ground: https://szaster.github.io/Your-Breaking-News/ | GitHub: https://github.com/szaster/Your-Breaking-News/

- Description: Web application that aggregates articles from various news sources aiming to deliver unbiased information to readers.
- · Role: Designed and implemented user interface, worked on functionality, and business logic of the app.
- Tools/languages: HTML, Javascript, jQuery, CSS, Materialize CSS.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# General Chemistry Instructor University of Houston

2008 - 2010, January 2020 - present

- Developed weekly lectures, tests, and problem solving sessions for 50+ students;
- · Demonstrated techniques of the proper and safe laboratory equipment usage.

Research Assistant 2008 - 2017

## **University of Houston**

- Built theoretical models of quantum optical systems using Wolfram Language and Wolfram Mathematica;
- Published results in peer-reviewed publications, participated in conferences;
- Best graduate student poster award at Theoretical Chemistry Conference Texas A&M University.

2012

# **EDUCATION**

### The University of Texas at Austin

- A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars & React;
- Wrote complex full stack applications with multiple models and data associations, implemented user authentication;
- · Designed and developed responsive full stack web applications both independently and in a group setting;
- Acquired extensive experience in browser-based technologies, server side deployment, databases, and quality assurance.

Certificate: Full Stack Developer. 2020

**University of Houston** 

Degree: PhD, Theoretical Physical Chemistry

National Technical University of Ukraine 'Kyiv Polytechnic Institute'

Degree: Master's; Major: Physics, Education